Register of the Salvadoran subject collection, 1976-1994
Hoover Institution Archives
Salvadoran subject collection,
1976-1994
XX796
4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 videotape cassette (3.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, serial issues, pamphlets, flyers, press releases, other printed matter, and video tape, relating to political conditions, guerrilla warfare, and civil rights in El Salvador.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
El Salvador--Politics and government--1979-1992.; El Salvador--History--1979-1992.; Guerrillas--El Salvador.; Civil rights--El Salvador.; El Salvador.; Video tapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1976-1993. (Boxes 1-3)
  Reports, program statements, transcripts, press releases, flyers, printed material, map and miscellany
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1980-1987. (Box 4)
  Serial issues and printed drawing
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1987. (Tape cabinet)
  Videocassette recording
Container List
*See card catalog for increments that may have been received since December 1994
- SUBJECT FILE, 1976-1993
  - General. Reports, serial issues, letter, pamphlet, clippings, flyers, circulars, and bulletins, 1976-1990. Includes material relating to the Fuerzas Armadas de la Resistencia Nacional, Partido Comunista de El Salvador, Ejercito Revolucionario de Pueblo, Frente Democratico Revolucionario, and Salvadoran refugees in Mexico and Costa Rica. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Box 1., Folder 1-3)
  - General (Box 2., Folder 1-4)
  - Elections. Reports, 1984-1989 (Folder 5)
  - Frente de Accion Popular Unificada (FAPU). Serial issues, political platform, and a flyer, 1980 (Folder 6)
  - Frente Faribundo Marti para la Liberacion Nacional (FMLN). Reports, flyers, serial issues, program statements, circulars, radio broadcast transcripts, pamphlets, and press releases, 1980-1990. Includes statements by former guerrilla leaders, distributed by United States embassy, 1987, and map of guerrilla activity prepared by Central Intelligence Agency, 1991. SEE ALSO: AUDIOVISUAL FILE (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - Human rights. Reports, letters, position paper, and a pamphlet, ca. 1983-1990 (Folder 2)
  - Partido Comunista de El Salvador. Reports relating to the Seventh Party Congress, 1979 (Folder 3-4)
  - Peace negotiations. Official texts of agreements, 1989-1991, and pamphlet describing peace process, 1993 (Folder 5)
  - United States. Speech by Nestor D. Sanchez, Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Inter-American Affairs, concerning United States military assistance and operations of Salvadoran armed forces, 1983 (Folder 6)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1980-1987.
  - Serial issues and printed drawing (Box 4.)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1987.
  - Videocassette recording entitled Tiempo de Victoria, produced by Radio Venceremos, 1987 (Box Tape cabinet)